<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.amk.ca/qel/qel.css"?>
<quotations>
<quotation id="mc1">
<p>
"We are never quits with those who oblige us," was Dantes'
reply; "for when we do not owe them money, we owe them
gratitude."
</p>

<author>Alexandre Dumas</author> 
<source><cite>The Count of Monte Cristo</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="mc2">
<p>
"Drunk, if you like; so much the worse for those who fear
wine, for it is because they have bad thoughts which they
are afraid the liquor will extract from their hearts;"
</p>

<author>Alexandre Dumas</author> 
<source><cite>The Count of Monte Cristo</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="mc3">
<p>
"How strange," continued the king, with some asperity; "the
police think that they have disposed of the whole matter
when they say, 'A murder has been committed,' and especially
so when they can add, 'And we are on the track of the guilty
persons.'"
</p>

<author>Alexandre Dumas</author> 
<source><cite>The Count of Monte Cristo</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="mc4">
<p>
[T]o learn is not to know; there are the learners and the
learned. Memory makes the one, philosophy the other.
</p>

<author>Alexandre Dumas</author> 
<source><cite>The Count of Monte Cristo</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tya1">
<p>
[L]earn ever to separate the king and the principle of royalty. The
king is but man; royalty is the spirit of God. When you are in doubt
as to which you should serve, forsake the material appearance for the
invisible principle, for this is everything.
</p>

<author>Alexandre Dumas</author> 
<source><cite>Twenty Years After</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="ge1">
<p>
Mrs. Joe was a very clean housekeeper, but had an exquisite art of making
her cleanliness more uncomfortable and unacceptable than the dirt itself.
Cleanliness is next to Godliness, and some people do the same by religion.
</p>

<author>Charles Dickens</author> 
<source><cite>Great Expectations</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc1">
<p>
All tribal myths are true, for a given value of 'true'.
</p>

<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc2">
<p>
Something as artificial and human as an hour wouldn't last five minutes 
here.
</p>

<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc3">
<p>
Logic is a wonderful thing but doesn't always beat actual thought.
</p>

<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc4">
<p>
Rincewind awoke with a scream, to get it over with.
</p>

<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc5">
<p>
Creators aren't gods. They make places, which is quite hard. It's men 
that make gods. This explains a lot.
</p>

<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc6">
<p>
He hated weapons, and not just because they'd so often been aimed at 
him. You got into <em>more</em> trouble if you had a weapon. People shot you 
instantly if they thought you were going to shoot them. But if you were 
unarmed, they often stopped to talk. Admittedly, they tended to say 
things like, 'You'll <em>never</em> guess what we're going to <em>do</em> to you, pal,' 
but that took <em>time</em>. And Rincewind could do a lot with a few seconds. 
He could use them to live longer in.
</p>

<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc7">
<p>
It had been going so well. They almost seemed up to speed. This may have 
been what caused Ponder to act like the man who, having so far fallen 
a hundred feet without any harm, believes that the last few inches to 
the ground will be a mere formality.
</p>

<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc8">
<p>
There's a certain kind of manager who is known by his call of 'My door is 
always open' and it is probably a good idea to beat yourself to death with 
your own CV rather than work for him.
</p>

<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc9">
<p>
And he was pretty sure that there was no way you could get a cross between 
a human and a sheep. If there was, people would definitely have found out 
by now, especially in the more isolated rural districts.
</p>

<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc10">
<p>
'Haven't you noticed that by running away you end up in more trouble?'
</p>

<p>
'Yes, but you see, you can run away from <em>that</em>, too,' said Rincewind. 
'That's the beauty of the system. Dead is only for once, but running 
away is for ever.'
</p>

<p>
'Ah, but it is said that a coward dies a thousand deaths, while a hero 
dies only one.'
</p>

<p>  
'Yes, but it's the <em>important</em> one.'
</p>

<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc11">
<p>
Rincewind paused. He had always been the foremost exponent of the <em>from</em> 
rather than the <em>to</em> of running.
</p>

<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc12">
<p>
But still, one of the most basic rules for survival on any planet is never 
to upset someone wearing black leather.*
</p>

<p>
* This is why protesters against the wearing of animal skins by humans
unaccountably fail to throw their paint over Hell's Angels.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="lc13">
<p>
That was the thing about fire. If you saw one, everyone went to put it 
out. Fire spread like wildfire.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Last Continent</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tt1">
<p>
The world is made up of four elements: Earth, Air, Fire and Water. This
is a fact well known even to Corporal Nobbs. It's also wrong. There's a
fifth element, and generally it's called Surprise.
</p>

<p>
For example, the dwarfs found out how to turn lead into gold by doing it
the hard way. The difference between that and the easy way is that the
hard way works.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Truth</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tt2">
<p>
In fact he was incurably insane and hallucinated more or less constantly,
but by a remarkable stroke of lateral thinking his fellow wizards had
reasoned that, in that case, the whole business could be sorted out if
only they could find a formula that caused him to <em>hallucinate that he 
was completely sane.</em>*
</p>

<p>
* This is a very common hallucination, shared by most people.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Truth</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tt3"><p>
[']You know I've always wanted a paperless office--'
</p>
<p>
'Yes, Archchancellor, that's why you hide it all in cupboards and throw
it out of the window at night.'
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Truth</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tt4"><p>
There are, it has been said, two types of people in the world. There are
those who, when presented with a glass that is exactly half full, say:
this glass is half full. And then there are those who say: this glass is
half empty.
</p>
<p>
The world <em>belongs</em>, however, to those who can look at the glass and say:
'What's up with this glass? Excuse me? Excuse <em>me</em>? <em>This</em> is my glass?
I don't <em>think</em> so. <em>My</em> glass was full! <em>And</em> it was a bigger glass!
</p>
<p>
And at the other end of the bar the world is full of the other type of 
person, who has a broken glass, or a glass that has been carefully knocked
over (usually by one of the people calling for a larger glass), or who
had no glass at all, because they were at the back of the crowd and had
failed to catch the barman's eye.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Truth</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tt5"><p>
'And these are your reasons, my lord?'
</p>
<p>
'Do you think I have others?' said Lord Vetinari. 'My motives, as ever,
are entirely transparent.'
</p>
<p>
Hughnon reflected that 'entirely transparent' meant either that you could
see right through them or that you couldn't see them at all.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Truth</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tt6"><p>
It was hard to see Mr. Tulip's eyes, because of a certain puffiness 
probably caused by too much enthusiasm for things in bags.*
</p>
<p>
* Your Brain On Drugs is a terrible sight, but Mr. Tulip was living proof
of the fact that so was Your Brain on a cocktail of horse liniment, 
sherbet and powdered water-retention pills.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Truth</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tt7">
<p>
If his body was a temple, it was one of those strange ones where people
did odd things to animals in the basement, and if he watched what he ate
it was only to see it wriggle.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>The Truth</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="hf1">
<p>
'And there's the sign, Ridcully,' said the Dean. You <em>have</em> read it, I
assume. You know? The sign which says "Do not, under any circumstances,
open this door"?'
</p>
<p>
'Of course I've read it,' said Ridcully. 'Why d'yer think I want it
opened?'
</p>
<p>
'Er...why?' said the Lecturer in Recent Runes.
</p>
<p>
'To see why they wanted it shut, of course.'*
</p>
<p>
* This exchange contains almost all you need to know about human
civilisation. At least, those bits of it that are now under the sea, 
fenced off or still smoking.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Hogfather</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="hf2">
<p>
Downey stood up with some relief and walked over to his large drinks
cabinet. His hand hovered over the Guild's ancient and valuable 
tantalus, with its labelled decanters of Mur, Nig, Trop and Yksihw.*
</p>
<p>
* It's a sad and terrible thing that high-born folk really have thought
that the servants would be fooled if spirits were put into decanters that
were cunningly labelled <em>backwards</em>. And also throughout history the more
politically conscious butler has taken it on trust, and with rather more
justification, that his employers will not notice if the whisky is topped
up with eniru.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Hogfather</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="hf3">
<p>
'You can't give her that!' she screamed. 'It's not safe!'
</p>
<p>
IT'S A SWORD said the Hogfather. THEY'RE NOT <em>MEANT</em> TO BE SAFE.
</p>
<p>
'She's a child!' shouted Crumley.
</p>
<p>
IT'S EDUCATIONAL.
</p>
<p>
'What if she cuts herself?'
</p>
<p>
THAT WILL BE AN IMPORTANT LESSON.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Hogfather</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="hf4">
<p>
'I...<em>think</em> my name is Bilious. I'm the...I'm the Oh God of Hangovers.'
</p>
<p>
'There's a God of Hangovers?'
</p>
<p>
'An <em>oh god</em>,' he corrected. 'When people witness me, you see, they clutch 
their head and say <em>"Oh God..."</em> How many of you are standing here?'
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Hogfather</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="hf5">
<p>
'So mistletoe, in fact, symbolises mistletoe?'
</p>
<p>
'Exactly, Archchancellor,' said the Senior Wrangler, who was now just 
hanging on.
</p>
<p>
'Funny thing, that,' said Ridcully, in the same thoughtful tone of voice. 
'That statement is either so deep it would take a lifetime to fully 
comprehend every particle of its meaning, or it is a load of absolute tosh. 
Which is it, I wonder?'
</p>
<p>
'It could be both,' said the Senior Wrangler desperately.
</p>
<p> 
'And <em>that</em> comment,' said Ridcully, 'is either very perceptive, or very 
trite.'
</p>
<p>
'It might be bo--'
</p>
<p>
'Don't push it, Senior Wrangler.'
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Hogfather</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="hf6">
<p>
IT'S THE EXPRESSION ON THEIR LITTLE FACES I LIKE, said the Hogfather.
</p>
<p>
'You mean the sort of fear and awe and not knowing whether to laugh or cry 
or wet their pants?'
</p>
<p>
YES. NOW <em>THAT</em> IS WHAT I CALL BELIEF.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Hogfather</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="hf7">
<p>
Then the Dean repeated the mantra that has had such a marked effect on the 
progress of knowledge through the ages.
</p>
<p>
'Why don't we just mix up absolutely everything and see what happens?' he 
said.
</p>
<p>
And Ridcully responded with the traditional response.
</p>
<p>
'It's got to be worth a try,' he said.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Hogfather</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="hf8">
<p>
'I remember my father tellin' me some valuable advice about drinks,' said 
Ridcully. 'He said, "Son, never drink any drink with a paper umbrella in 
it, never drink any drink with a humourous name, and never drink any drink 
that changes colour when the last ingredient goes in. And never, ever, do 
this--"'
</p>
<p>
He dipped his finger into the beaker.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Hogfather</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="hf9">
<p>
While evidence says that the road to Hell is paved with good intentions, 
they're probably all on first steps.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Hogfather</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tot1">
<p>
Then you have The Story of the Emperor Who Had No Clothes.
</p>
<p>
But if you knew a bit more, it would be The Story of the Boy Who Got a
Well-Deserved Thrashing from His Dad for Being Rude to Royalty, and Was
Locked Up.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Thief of Time</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tot2">
<p>
Genius is always allowed some leeway, once the hammer has been pried
from its hands and the blood has been cleaned up.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Thief of Time</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tot3">
<p>
'Could get a bit repetitive, master' said Clodpool.
</p>
<p>
'That is because you don't yet know how to deal with time', said Wen. 'But
I will teach you to deal with time as you would deal with a coat, to be
worn when necessary and discarded when not.'
</p>
<p>
'Will I have to wash it?' said Clodpool.
</p>
<p>
Wen gave him a long, slow look. 'That was either a very complex piece of
thinking on your part, Clodpool, or you were just trying to overextend
a metaphor in a rather stupid way. Which do you think it was?'
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Thief of Time</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tot4">
<p>
When you look into the abyss, it's not supposed to wave back.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Thief of Time</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tot5">
<p>
'Sometimes I really think people ought to have to pass a <em>proper</em> exam
before they're allowed to be parents. Not just the practical, I mean.'
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Thief of Time</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tot5">
<p>
Susan stopped. Of course someone would be that stupid. Some humans
would do anything to see if it was possible to do it. If you put a large
switch in some cave somewhere, with a sign on it saying 'End-of-the-World
Switch. PLEASE DO NOT TOUCH', the paint wouldn't even have time to dry.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Thief of Time</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation id="tot6">
<p>
<em>In the Second Scroll of Wen the Eternally Surprised</em> a story is written
concerning one day when the apprentice Clodpool, in a rebellious mood, 
approached Wen and spake thusly:
</p>
<p>
'Master, what is the difference between a humanistic, monastic system of
belief in which wisdom is sought by means of an apparently nonsensical
system of questions and answers, and a lot of mystic gibberish made up on
the spur of the moment?'
</p>
<p>
Wen considered this for some time, and at last said: 'A fish!'
</p>
<p>
And Clodpool went away, satisfied.
</p>

<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Thief of Time</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Magicians and scientists are, on the face of it, poles apart. Certainly,
a group of people who often dress strangely, live in a world of their own,
speak a specialized language and frequently make statements that appear
to be in flagrant breach of common sense have nothing in common with a
group of people who often dress strangely, speak a specialized language,
live in ... er ...</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Science of Discworld</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
On Roundworld, things happen because the <em>things</em> want to happen.*</p>
<p>* In a manner of speaking. They happen because things obey the rules of
the universe. A rock has no detectable opinion about gravity.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Science of Discworld</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Sometimes, the best answer is a more interesting question.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Science of Discworld</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
This was turning out to be the longest winter in living memory, so long,
in fact, that living memory itself was being shortened as some of the
older citizens succumbed.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Science of Discworld</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Much human ingenuity has gone into finding the ultimate Before.</p>
<p>The current state of knowledge can be summarized thus:</p>
<p>In the beginning, there was nothing, which exploded.</p>
<p>Other theories about the ultimate start involve gods creating the universe
out of the ribs, entrails and testicles of their father.* There are quite a
lot of these. They are interesting, not for what they tell you about 
cosmology, but for what they say about people. Hey, kids, which part do you
think they made <em>your</em> town out of?</p>
<p>* Gods like a joke as much as anyone else.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Assassination was meat and drink to the Hunghung court; in fact, meat and
drink were often the means.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Interesting Times</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'I reckon it was some kind of firework. They're very big on fireworks here.'</p>
<p>'You mean the sort of things where you light the blue touch paper and stick
it up your nose?'*</p>
<p>* KIDS! Only very silly wizards with bad sinus trouble do this. <em>Sensible</em>
people go off to a roped-off enclosure where they can watch a heavily
protected man, in the middle distance, light (with the aid of a very long
pole) something that goes 'fsst'. And then they can shout 'Hooray'.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Interesting Times</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'It's just that his memory's bad. We had a bit of trouble on the way over.
I keep telling him, it's rape the <em>women</em> and set fire to the <em>houses</em>.'</p>
<p>'Rape?' said Rincewind. 'That's not very--'</p>
<p>'He's eighty-seven,' said Cohen. 'Don't go and spoil an old man's dreams.'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Interesting Times</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Probably the last sound heard before the Universe folded up like a paper
hat would be someone saying, 'What happens if I do this?'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Interesting Times</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'But there are causes worth dying for,' said Butterfly.</p>
<p>'No, there aren't! Because you've only got one life but you can pick up
another five causes on any street corner!'</p>
<p>'Good grief, how can you <em>live</em> with a philosophy like that?'</p>
<p>Rincewind took a deep breath.</p>
<p>'Continuously!'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Interesting Times</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
WITH HIM HERE, EVEN UNCERTAINTY IS UNCERTAIN. AND I'M NOT SURE EVEN ABOUT
THAT.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Interesting Times</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
WHAT IS SO SURPRISING ABOUT BACON?</p>
<p>'I don't know. I suppose it comes as something of a shock to the pig.'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Interesting Times</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'There's a lot of waiting in warfare,' said Boy Willie.</p>
<p>'Ah, yes,' said Mr. Saveloy. 'I've heard people say that. They say there's
long periods of boredom followed by short periods of excitement.'</p>
<p>'Not really, said Cohen. 'It's more like short periods of waiting followed
by long periods of being dead.'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Interesting Times</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
A crude hut of driftwood had been built on the long curve of the beach,
although describing it as 'built' was a slander on skilled crude hut 
builders throughout the ages; if the sea had simply been left to pile the
wood up it might have done a better job.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Moving Pictures</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
The senior wizard in a world of magic had the same prospects of long-term
employment as a pogo stick tester in a minefield.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Moving Pictures</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
What the Burser failed to consider was that no more bangs doesn't mean
they've stopped doing it, whatever it is. It just means they're doing it
<em>right</em>.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Moving Pictures</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Of course, it is very important to be sober when you take an exam. Many 
worthwhile careers in the street-cleaning, fruit-picking and 
subway-guitar-playing industries have been founded on a lack of 
understanding of this simple fact.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Moving Pictures</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
[N]o-one with their sleeves rolled up who walks purposefully with 
a piece of paper held conspicuously in their hand is ever challenged.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Moving Pictures</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
He'd looked at it's ramshackle organisation, such as it was, with the 
eye of a lifelong salesman. There seemed nowhere in it for him, but this
wasn't a problem. There was always room at the top.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Moving Pictures</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'She hwas dusting,' siad Mrs Whitlow, helpfully. When Mrs Whitlow was
in the grip of acute class consciousness she could create aitches where
nature never intended them to be.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Moving Pictures</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Probably only one person in the world had been interested in whether the
old man lived or died, and he'd been the first to know.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Moving Pictures</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
[I]nside every old person is a young person wondering what happened.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Moving Pictures</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
[T]here is only one thing in the world worse than being talked about, 
and that is not being talked about.</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
When I like people immensely I never tell their names to any one.  It 
seems like surrendering a part of them.</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
The commonest thing is delightful if one only hides it.</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
[T]he one charm of marriage is that it makes a life of deception 
necessary for both parties.</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
[E]very portrait that is painted with feeling is a portrait of the
artist, not of the sitter. The sitter is merely the accident, the
occasion. It is not he who is revealed by the painter; it is rather
the painter who, on the colored canvas, reveals himself.</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Laughter is not a bad beginning for a friendship, and it is the best
ending for one</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Now, the value of an idea has nothing whatsoever to do with the 
sincerity of the man who expresses it. Indeed, the probabilities 
are that the more insincere the man is, the more purely 
intellectual will the idea be, as in that case it will not be 
coloured by either his wants, his desires, or his prejudices.</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Nowadays people know the price of everything, and the value of 
nothing.</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Men marry because they are tired; women, because they are curious: 
both are disappointed.</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
When one is in love, one always begins by deceiving one's self, and 
one always ends by deceiving others.</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
He gives you good advice, I suppose. People are very fond of giving 
away what they need most themselves.</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Experience was of no ethical value. It was merely the name we gave 
to our mistakes.</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
To get back my youth I would do anything in the world, except take 
exercise, get up early, or be respectable.</p>
<author>Oscar Wilde</author> 
<source><cite>The Picture of Dorian Gray</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'And what would humans be without love?'</p>
<p>RARE, said Death.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
He sighed again. People were always trying this sort of thing. On the 
other hand, it was quite interesting to watch, and at least this was
a bit more original than the usual symbolic chess game, which Death 
always dreaded because he could never remember how the knight was supposed
to move.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
* The vermine is a small black and white relative of the lemming, found
in the cold Hublandish regions. It's skin is rare and highly valued,
especially by the vermine itself; the selfish little bastard will do 
anything rather than let go of it.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
This was the type of thief that could steal the initiative, the moment and
the words right out of your mouth.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
These weren't the normal city watch, cautious and genially corrupt. These
were walking slabs of muscle and they were absolutely unbribable, if only
because the Patrician could outbid anyone else.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
After that one thing sort of led to another and pretty soon everyone was
fighting to get something - either away, out or even.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
It wasn't blood in general he couldn't stand the sight of, it was just his
blood in particular that was so upsetting.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
* Of course, Ankh-Morpork's citizens had always claimed that the river 
water was incredibly pure in any case. Any water that had passed through
so many kidneys, they reasoned, had to be very pure indeed.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'My father always said that death is but a sleep,' said Conina.</p>
<p>'Yes, the hat told me that,' said Rincewind, as they turned down a narrow,
crowded street between white adobe walls. 'But the way I see it, it's a
lot harder to get up in the morning.'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'My father always said that it was pointless to undertake a direct attack
against an enemy extensively armed with efficient projectile weapons,'
she said.</p>
<p>Rincewind, who knew Cohen's normal method of speech, gave her a look of
disbelief.</p>
<p>'Well, what he <em>actually</em> said,' she added, 'was never enter an arse-
kicking contest with a porcupine.'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
* The Hashishim, who derived their name from the vast quantities of
<em>hashish</em> they consumed, were unique among vicious killers in being
both deadly and, at the same time, inclined to giggle, groove to 
interesting patterns of light and shade on their terrible knife blades
and, in extreme cases, fall over.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
[A] popular spell at the time was Pelepel's Temporal Compressor, which
on one occasion resulted in a race of giant reptiles being created,
evolving, spreading, flourishing and then being destroyed in the space
of about five minutes, leaving only its bones in the earth to mislead
forthcoming generations completely.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
The truth isn't easily pinned to a page. In the bathtub of history the
truth is harder to hold than the soap, and much more difficult to find...</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'I don't trust this man,' said Nijel. 'I try not to judge from first
impressions, but I definitly think he's up to no good.'</p>
<p>'He had you thrown in a snake pit!'</p>
<p>'Perhaps I should have taken the hint.'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Wizards didn't kill ordinary people because a) they seldom noticed them
and b) it wasn't considered sporting and c) besides, who'd do all the 
cooking and growing food and things. And killing a brother wizard with 
magic was nigh-well impossible on account of the layers of protective 
spells that any cautious wizard maintained about his person at all times.*</p>
<p>* Of course, wizards often killed each other by ordinary, non-magical
means, but this was perfectly allowable and death by assassination was
considered natural causes for a wizard.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Some people think this is paranoia, but it isn't. Paranoids only think
everyone is out to get them. Wizards <em>know</em> it.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'I'm not going to ride on a magic carpet!' he hissed. 'I'm afraid of 
grounds!'</p>
<p>'You mean heights,' said Conina. 'And stop being silly.'</p>
<p>'I know what I mean! It's the grounds that kill you!'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
There was a respectful silence, as there always is when large sums of
money have just passed away.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Many people who had got to know Rincewind had come to treat him as a
sort of two-legged miner's canary, and tended to assume that if 
Rincewind was still upright and not actually running then some hope
remained.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'This is fun,' said Creosote. 'Me, robbing my own treasury. If I catch
myself I can have myself flung into the snake pit.'</p>
<p>'But you could throw yourself on your mercy,' said Conina, running a 
paranoid eye over the dusty stonework.</p>
<p>'Oh, no. I think I would have to teach me a lesson, as an example to
myself.'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'I can't hear anything,' said Nijel loudly. Nijel was one of those people
who, if you say "don't look now", would immediately swivel his head like
an owl on a turntable.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Too much magic could wrap time and space around itself, and that wasn't
good news for the kind of person who had grown used to things like effects
following things like causes.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
They suffered from the terrible delusion that something could be done.
They seemed prepared to make the world the way they wanted or die in the
attempt, and the trouble with dying in the attempt was that you died in
the attempt.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'Poor I don't mind,' said the Seriph. 'It's sobriety that is giving me
difficulties.'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Take it from me, there's nothing more terrible than someone out to do 
the world a favour.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Wizards don't like philosophy very much. As far as they are concerned,
one hand clapping makes a sound like 'cl'.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Sourcery</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
They thought that you could see life through books but you couldn't, the
reason being that the words got in the way.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Carpe Jugulum</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Mirrors had lead to one of the Church's innumerable schisms, one side 
saying that since they encouraged vanity they were bad, and the other
side saying that since they reflected the goodness of Om they were holy.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Carpe Jugulum</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Lancre operated on the feudal system, which was to say, everyone feuded
all the time and handed on the fight to their descendants. The chips on
some shoulders had been passed down for generations.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Carpe Jugulum</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
The smug mask of virtue triumphant could be almost as horrible as the
face of wickedness revealed.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Carpe Jugulum</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
What had she ever earned? The reward for toil had been more toil. If you
dug the best ditches they gave you a bigger shovel.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Carpe Jugulum</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
She'd never, ever asked for anything in return. And the trouble with not
asking for anything in return was that sometimes you didn't get it.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Carpe Jugulum</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
There was something... sort of <em>damp</em> about him, the kind of helpless
hopelessness that made people angry rather than charitable, the total
certainty that if the whole <em>world</em> was a party he'd still find the
kitchen.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Carpe Jugulum</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'Will it be enough to know that the world is your oyster?'</p>
<p>Her forehead wrinkled in perplexity. 'Why should I want it to be some
nasty little sea creature?' she said.</p>
<p>'Because they get eaten alive,' said the Count.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Carpe Jugulum</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
She was not, herself, hugely in favour of motherhood in general. Obviously
it was necessary, but it wasn't exactly <em>difficult</em>. Even cats managed it.
But women acted as if they'd been given a medal that entitled them to
boss people around. It was as if, just because they'd got the label which
said 'mother', everyone else got a tiny part of the label that said 
'child'...
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Carpe Jugulum</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
The result would have been called primitive even by people who were too
primitive to have a word yet for 'primitive'.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Carpe Jugulum</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'Oh, <em>we</em>'re always all right. You remember that. We happen to other 
people.'
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Carpe Jugulum</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
* The role of the lower intestine in the efforts to build a better nation
is one that is often neglected by historians.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Carpe Jugulum</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Certain things have to happen before other things. Gods play games with
the fates of men. But first they have to get all the pieces on the board,
and look all over the place for the dice.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Soul Music</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
The question seldom addressed is <em>where</em> Medusa had snakes. Underarm hair
is an even more embarrassing problem when it keeps biting the top of the
deodorant bottle.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Soul Music</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Susan hated Literature. She'd much prefer to read a good book.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Soul Music</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
That question was less stupid; though you asked it in a profoundly stupid
way.
</p>
<source>Futurama</source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
He was not, by the standard definitions, a bad man; in the same way a
plague-bearing rat is not, from a dispassionate point of view, a bad
animal.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Soul Music</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Imp hesitated, as people do when, after having used a language all their 
lives, they're told to 'say something'.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Soul Music</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'We'll practise as we go along,' said Glod. 'Welcome to the world of
professional musicianship.'
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Soul Music</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Susan looked at the mess sizzling in the huge frying-pan. It wasn't a
sight to be seen on an empty stomach, although it could probably cause
one.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Soul Music</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'You're a musician, ain't you?' said Glod. 'What do you think you do?'</p>
<p>'I hits 'em with de hammers,' said Lias, one of nature's drummers.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Soul Music</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
It was eight in the morning, a time when drinkers are trying either to
forget who they are or to remember where they live.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Soul Music</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
C. M. O. T. Dibbler liked to be up at first light, in case there was
an opportunity to sell a worm to the early bird.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Soul Music</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'We need to get it together if we're going to wow them at the Festival,' 
said Crash.</p>
<p>'What, you mean ... like ... learn to play?' said Jimbo.</p>
<p>'No! Music With Rocks In just happens. If you go around <em>learning</em> you'll
never get anywhere,' said Crash.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Soul Music</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
The thought was flooding into his mind, and not for the first time, 
that Mr. Clete was not playing with a full orchestra, that he was one of
those people who built their own hot madness out of sane and chilly parts.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Soul Music</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Witches generally act as layers-out of the dead as well as midwives; there
were plenty of people in Lancre for whom Nanny Ogg's face had been the 
first and last thing they'd ever seen, which had probably made the bit in
the middle seem quite uneventful by comparison.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Mustrum Ridcully did a lot for rare species. For one thing, he kept them
rare.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Using metaphor in front of a man as unimaginative as Ridcully was like a
red flag to a bu-- was like putting something very annoying in front of
someone who was annoyed by it.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
People were always telling him to make something of his life, and that's
what he wanted to do. He wanted to make a bed of it.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'But all them things exist,' said Nanny Ogg.</p>
<p>'That's no call to go around believing in them. It only encourages 'em'.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'I never said nothing,' said Nanny Ogg mildly.</p>
<p>'I know you never! I could <em>hear</em> you not saying anything! You've got 
the loudest silences I ever did hear from anyone who wasn't dead!'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Nanny Ogg had a pragmatic attitude to the truth; she told it if it was 
convenient and she couldn't be bothered to make up something more
interesting.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
She was an incredibly comfortable person to be around, partly because
she had a mind so broad it could accommodate three football fields and a
bowling alley.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
The shortest unit of <em>time</em> in the multiverse is the New York second,
defined as the period of time between the traffic lights turning green
and the cab behind you honking.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Dwarfs are generally scared of heights, since they don't often have the
opportunity to get used to them.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Magrat says a broomstick is one of them sexual metaphor things.*</p>
<p>* Although this is a phallusy.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'It's certain death anyway,' said Ridcully. 'That's the thing about Death,
certainty.'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author> 
<source><cite>Lords and Ladies</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
A key to the understanding of all religion is that a god's idea of 
amusement is Snakes and Ladders with greased rungs.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Wyrd Sisters</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
It was dawning on him that the pleasures of the flesh were pretty sparse 
without the flesh. Suddenly life wasn't worth living. The fact that he 
wasn't living it didn't cheer him up at all.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Wyrd Sisters</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'If I'd had to buy you, you wouldn't be worth the price.'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Wyrd Sisters</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
The days followed one another patiently. Right back at the beginning of 
the multiverse they had tried all passing at the same time, and it hadn't 
worked.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Wyrd Sisters</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Demons were like genies or philosophy professors - if you didn't word
things <em>exactly</em> right, they delighted in giving you absolutely accurate
nd completely misleading answers.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Wyrd Sisters</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Destiny was funny stuff, he knew. You couldn't trust it. Often you couldn't
even see it. Just when you knew you had it cornered, it turned out to be
something else - coincidence, maybe, or providence.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Wyrd Sisters</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
This was real. This was more real even than reality. This was history.
It might not be true, but that had nothing to do with it.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Wyrd Sisters</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
This is Art holding a Mirror up to Life. That's why everything is exactly
the wrong way round.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Wyrd Sisters</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Eh! sire, that is the fate of truth; she is a stern companion; she bristles 
all over with steel; she wounds those whom she attacks, and sometimes him 
who speaks her.</p>
<author>Alexandre Dumas</author>
<source><cite>The Viscomte de Bragelonne</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
My friend, the pleasures to which we are not accustomed oppress us more than 
the griefs with which we are familiar.</p>
<author>Alexandre Dumas</author>
<source><cite>The Viscomte de Bragelonne</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
ABOYNE (vb.)</p>
<p>To beat an expert at a game of skill by playing so appallingly 
that none of his clever tactics or strategies are of any use to him.</p>
<author>Douglas Adams</author>
<author>John Lloyd</author>
<source><cite>The Meaning of Liff</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
CLIXBY (adj.)</p>
<p>Politely rude. Briskly vague. Firmly uninformative.</p>                     
<author>Douglas Adams</author>
<author>John Lloyd</author>
<source><cite>The Meaning of Liff</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
All assassins had a full-length mirror in their rooms, because it would 
be a terrible insult to anyone to kill them when you were badly dressed.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Pyramids</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
You scrimped and saved to send them to the best schools, and then they
went and paid you back by getting educated.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Pyramids</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Seeing, contrary to popular wisdom, isn't believing. It's where belief
stops, because it isn't needed any more.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Pyramids</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
It is a hopeless endeavour to attract people to a theatre unless they
can be first brought to believe that they will never get in.</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Nicholas Nickleby</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'The major difference between a thing that might go wrong and a thing 
that cannot possibly go wrong is that when a thing that cannot possibly
go wrong goes wrong it usually turns out to be impossible to get at or 
repair.'</p>
<author>Douglas Adams</author>
<source><cite>Mostly Harmless</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
The thing he realized about the windows was this: because they had been
converted into openable windows <em>after</em> they had first been designed to
be impregnable, they were, in fact, much less secure than if they had 
been designed as openable windows in the first place.</p>
<author>Douglas Adams</author>
<source><cite>Mostly Harmless</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
One said, That is the point. The word is <em>him</em>. Becoming a personality 
<em>is</em> inefficient. We don't want it to spread. Supposing gravity developed
a personality? Supposing it decided to <em>like</em> people?</p>
<p>One said, Got a crush on them, sort of thing?</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Reaper Man</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
...young men not being as a class remarkable for modesty or self-denial,
especially when there is a lady in the case, when, if they colour at all,
it is rather their practise to colour the story, and not themselves.</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Nicholas Nickleby</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Pride is one of the seven deadly sins; but it cannot be the pride of a 
mother in her children, for that is a compound of two cardinal virtues--
faith and hope.</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Nicholas Nickleby</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
There are many pleasant fictions of the law in constant operation, but 
there is not one so pleasant or practically humorous as that which supposes
every man to be of equal value in its impartial eye, and the benefits of 
all laws to be equally attainable by all men, without the smallest 
reference to the furniture of their pockets.</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Nicholas Nickleby</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
When men are about to commit, or sanction the commission of some injustice,
it is not uncommon for them to express pity for the object either of that
or some parallel proceeding, and to feel themselves, at the time, quite
virtuous and moral, and immensely superior to those who express no pity at
all. This is a kind of upholding of faith above works, and is very
comfortable.</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Nicholas Nickleby</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Look to yourself, and heed this warning that I give you! Your day is past,
and night is coming on--</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Nicholas Nickleby</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
'It's not old Windle. Old Windle was a lot older!'</p>
<p>'Older? Older than <em>dead</em>?'</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Reaper Man</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Was that justice? Was that a proper reward for being a firm believer in
reincarnation for almost 130 years? You come back as a <em>corpse</em>?</p>
<p>No wonder the undead were traditionally considered to be very angry.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Reaper Man</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Intellectually, Ridcully maintained his position for two reasons. One was
that he never, ever, changed his mind about anything. The other was that
it took him several minutes to understand any new idea put to him, and
this is a very valuable trait in a leader, because anything anyone is 
still trying to explain to you after two minutes is probably important and
anything they give up after a mere minute or so is almost certainly 
something they shouldn't have been bothering you with in the first place.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Reaper Man</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Ridcully was simple-minded. This doesn't mean stupid. It just means that
he could only think properly about things if he cut away all the complicated
bits around the edges.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Reaper Man</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
No naked little men sat on the summit dispensing wisdom, because the first
thing the truly wise man works out is that sitting around on mountaintops
gives you not only haemorrhoids but <em>frostbitten</em> haemorrhoids.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Reaper Man</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
As yet unmeasured, but believed to be faster than light owing to its 
ability to move so quickly out of light's way.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>The Science of Discworld</cite></source>
</quotation>
<note>On the speed of Dark</note>
<quotation>
<p>
He had noted that with older people. They often try to control younger,
more popular and vivacious people; usually due to the fact that they are
jealous of the qualities the younger people have and they lack. These
inadequacies are disguised with a benign, protective attitide. </p>
<author>Irvine Welsh</author>
<source><cite>Trainspotting</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Ah wonder if anybody this side of the Atlantic has ever bought a baseball
bat with playing baseball in mind.</p>
<author>Irvine Welsh</author>
<source><cite>Trainspotting</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
Nanny also recalled her as being rather thoughtful and shy, as if trying 
to reduce the amount of world she took up.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Maskerade</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
No one had asked her, before she was born, whether she wanted a lovely 
personality or whether she'd prefer, say, a miserable personality but a 
body that could take size 9 in dresses. Instead, people would take pains
to tell her that beauty was only skin-deep, as if a man ever fell for
an attractive pair of kidneys.</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Maskerade</cite></source>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
A one-question geek test. If you get the joke, you're a geek: Seen on 
a California license plate on a VW Beetle: 'FEATURE'...
</p>
<author>Joshua D. Wachs</author>
</quotation>
<quotation>
<p>
If ignorance is bliss, is omniscience hell?
</p>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>What is good? - All that heightens the feeling of power, the will 
to power, power itself in man.</p>
<p>What is bad? - All that proceeds from weakness.</p>
<p>What is happiness? - The feeling that power <em>increases</em> - that a 
resistance is overcome.</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>The Antichrist</cite> Aphorism 2</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>The weak and ill-constituted shall perish: first principle of <em>our</em> 
philanthropy. And one shall help them to do so.</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>The Antichrist</cite> Aphorism 2</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>I call an animal, a species, an individual depraved when it loses 
its instincts, when it chooses, when it <em>prefers</em> what is harmful to 
it.</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>The Antichrist</cite> Aphorism 6</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>Pity on the whole thwarts the law of evolution, which is the law of 
<em>selection</em>.</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>The Antichrist</cite> Aphorism 7</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>The very word 'Christianity' is a misunderstanding--at bottom there was only 
one Christian, and he died on the cross.</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>The Antichrist</cite> Aphorism 39</source>
<note>Often misquoted as "The last Christian died on the cross"</note>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
He's dead. However, credit where it's due, he hasn't let that stop him.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Monstrous Regiment</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
So what we have here is a country that tries to run itself on the commandments 
of a god who, the people feel, may be wearing his underpants on his head. Has he 
Abominated underpants?
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Monstrous Regiment</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
[T]he interests of Ankh-Morpork are the interests of all money-lov--oops, sorry, 
all <em>freedom</em>-loving people everywhere
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Monstrous Regiment</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Most of the vampire families were highly nobby. You never knew who was
connected to who... not just connected to who, in fact, but to whom. Whoms 
were likely to be far more trouble than your common everyday who.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Monstrous Regiment</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
'I've starved a few times. There's no future in it. Ate a man's leg when we 
were snowed up in the Ibblestarn campaign but, fair's fair, he ate mine.' He 
looked at their faces. 'Well, it's not on, is it, eating your own leg? You'd 
probably go blind.'
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Monstrous Regiment</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Lieutenant Blouse was standing in the middle of the floor in his breeches and 
shirtsleeves, holding a sabre. Polly was no expert in these matters, but she 
thought she recognised the stylish, flamboyant pose as the one beginners tend 
to use just before they're stabbed through the heart by a more experienced 
fighter.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Monstrous Regiment</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
'Good evening, gentlemen!' said the vampire. 'Please pay attention. I am a 
<em>reformed</em> vampire, which is to say, I am a bundle of suppressed instincts 
held together with spit and coffee. It would be wrong to say that violent, 
tearing carnage does not come easily to me. It's <em>not</em> tearing your 
throats out that doesn't come easily to me. Please don't make it any harder.'
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Monstrous Regiment</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
To reign is worth ambition, though in Hell:<br/>
Better to reign in Hell than serve in Heaven.
</p>
<author>John Milton</author>
<source><cite>Paradise Lost</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
For who can yet believe, though after loss,<br/>
That all these puissant legions, whose exile<br/>
Hath emptied Heaven, shall fail to re-ascend,<br/>
Self-raised, and repossess their native seat?
</p>
<author>John Milton</author>
<source><cite>Paradise Lost</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
who overcomes<br/>
By force hath overcome but half his foe.
</p>
<author>John Milton</author>
<source><cite>Paradise Lost</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Wishes needed thought. She was never likely to say, out loud, 'I wish that I 
could marry a handsome prince,' but knowing that if you did you'd probably 
open the door to find a stunned prince, a tied-up priest and a Nac Mac Feegle 
grinning cheerfully and ready to act as Best Man definitely made you watch what 
you said.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>A Hat Full of Sky</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Admittedly - and it took some admitting - he was a lot less of a twit than he 
had been. On the other hand, there had been such a lot of twit to begin with.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>A Hat Full of Sky</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
The beef stew tasted, indeed, just like beef stew and not, just to take an 
example <em>completely</em> and <em>totally</em> at random, stew made out of 
the last poor girl who'd worked here.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>A Hat Full of Sky</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
'Mistress Weatherwax is the head witch, then, is she?'<br/>
'Oh no!' said Miss Level, looking shocked. 'Witches are all equal. We don't 
have head witches. That's <em>quite</em> against the spirit of witchcraft.'<br/>
'Oh, I see,' said Tiffany.<br/>
'Besides,' Miss Level added, 'Mistress Weatherwax would never allow that sort 
of thing.'
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>A Hat Full of Sky</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
To be looked at by Annagramma was to know that you'd already taken up too much 
of her valuable time.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>A Hat Full of Sky</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
'I had a lot of voles last night,' said Mistress Weatherwax over her shoulder.<br/>
'Yes, but <em>you</em> didn't actually eat them, did you?' said Tiffany. 'It 
was the owl that <em>actually</em> ate them.'<br/>
'Technic'ly, yes,' Mistress Weatherwax admitted. 'But if you think you've been 
eating voles all night you'd be amazed how much you don't want to eat anything 
next morning. Or ever again.'
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>A Hat Full of Sky</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
So weiss jeder aus Erfahrung, wie schnell der Traeumende einen starken an ihn 
dringenden Ton, zum Beispiel Glockenlaeuten, Kanonenschuesse in seinen Traum 
verflicht, das heisst aus ihm hinterdrein erklaert, so dass er zuerst die 
veranlassenden Umstaende, dann jenen Ton zu erleben meint.
</foreign></p>
<p>
Everyone knows from experience how fast the dreamer can incorporate into his 
dream a loud sound he hears, bell ringing, for example, or cannon fire, how he 
can explain it <em>after the fact</em> from his dream, so that he believes he 
is experiencing first the occasioning factors, and then that sound.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
Of First and Last Things, Aphorism 13</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Das Traumdenken wird uns jetzt so leicht, weil wir in ungeheuren 
Entwickelungsstrecken der Menschheit gerade auf diese Form des phantastischen 
und wohlfeilen Erklaerens aus dem ersten beliebigen Einfalle heraus so gut 
eingedrillt worden sind. Insofern ist der Traum eine Erholung fuer das Gehirn, 
welches am Tage den strengeren Anforderungen an das Denken zu genuegen hat, wie 
sie von der hoeheren Cultur gestellt werden.
</foreign></p>
<p>Dream-thought is so easy for us now because, during mankind's immense periods 
of development, we have been so well drilled in just this form of fantastic and 
cheap explanation from the first, best idea. In this way dreaming is recuperation 
for a brain which must satisfy by day the stricter demands made on thought by 
higher culture.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
Of First and Last Things, Aphorism 13</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Allem Glauben zu Grunde liegt die Empfindung des Angenehmen oder Schmerzhaften 
in Bezug auf das empfindende Subject. Eine neue dritte Empfindung als Resultat 
zweier vorangegangenen einzelnen Empfindungen ist das Urtheil in seiner 
niedrigsten Form.
</foreign></p>
<p>All belief is based on the <em>feeling of pleasure or pain</em> in relation to the 
feeling subject. A new, third feeling as the result of two preceeding feelings 
is judgement in its lowest form.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
Of First and Last Things, Aphorism 18</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Ein wesentlicher Nachtheil, welchen das Aufhoeren metaphysischer Ansichten mit 
sich bringt, liegt darin, dass das Individuum zu streng seine kurze Lebenszeit 
in's Auge fasst und keine staerkeren Antriebe empfaengt, an dauerhaften, fuer 
Jahrhunderte angelegten Institutionen zu bauen
</foreign></p>
<p>One crucial disadvantage about the end of metaphysical views is that the 
individual looks his own short life span too squarely in the eye and feels no 
strong incentive to build on enduring institutions, designed for the ages.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
Of First and Last Things, Aphorism 22</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Man glaubt einer Philosophie etwas Gutes nachzusagen, wenn man sie als Ersatz 
der Religion fuer das Volk hinstellt.
</foreign></p>
<p>One thinks he is speaking well of philosophy when he presents it as a 
substitute religion for the people.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
Of First and Last Things, Aphorism 27</source>

</quotation>
<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Der Irrthum hat den Menschen so tief, zart, erfinderisch gemacht, eine solche 
Bluethe, wie Religionen und Kuenste, herauszutreiben. Das reine Erkennen waere 
dazu ausser Stande gewesen.
</foreign></p>
<p><em>Error</em> has made man so deep, delicate, inventive as to bring forth such 
blossoms as religion and arts. Pure knowledge would never have been capable of it.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
Of First and Last Things, Aphorism 29</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Ohne die Irrthuemer, welche in den Annahmen der Moral liegen, waere der Mensch 
Thier geblieben. So aber hat er sich als etwas Hoeheres genommen und sich 
strengere Gesetze auferlegt. Er hat desshalb einen Hass gegen die der Thierheit 
naeher gebliebenen Stufen
</foreign></p>
<p>Without the errors inherent in the postulates of morality, man would have 
remained an animal. But as it is he has taken himself to be something higher 
and has imposed stricter laws upon himself. He therefore has a hatred of those 
stages of man that remain closer to the animal state.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 40</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Die Kuerze des menschlichen Lebens verleitet zu manchen irrthuemlichen 
Behauptungen ueber die Eigenschaften des Menschen.
</foreign></p>
<p>The brevity of human life misleads us to many an erroneous assertion 
about the qualities of man's feelings.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 41</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Die Menschen, welche jetzt grausam sind, muessen uns als Stufen frueherer 
Culturen gelten, welche uebrig geblieben sind: das Gebirge der Menschheit 
zeigt hier einmal die tieferen Formationen, welche sonst versteckt liegen, 
offen. ... Sie zeigen uns, was wir Alle waren, und machen uns erschrecken: 
aber sie selber sind so wenig verantwortlich, wie ein Stueck Granit dafuer, 
dass es Granit ist.
</foreign></p>
<p>We must think of men who are cruel today as stages of <em>earlier 
cultures</em>, which have been left over ... They show us what we <em>all</em> 
were, and frighten us. But they themselves are as little responsible as a 
piece of granite for being granite.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 43</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Der Grund, wesshalb der Maechtige dankbar ist, ist dieser. Sein Wohlthaeter 
hat sich durch seine Wohlthat an der Sphaere des Maechtigen gleichsam 
vergriffen und sich in sie eingedraengt: nun vergreift er sich zur Vergeltung 
wieder an der Sphaere des Wohlthaeters durch den Act der Dankbarkeit. Es ist 
eine mildere Form der Rache.
</foreign></p>
<p>The powerful man feels gratitude for the following reason: through his good 
deed, his benefactor has, as it were, violated the powerful man's sphere and 
penetrated it. Now through his act of gratitude the powerful man requites 
himself by violating the sphere of the benefactor. It is a milder form of 
revenge.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 44</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Freilich solle man Mitleiden bezeugen, aber sich hueten, es zu haben: denn die 
Ungluecklichen seien nun einmal so dumm, dass bei ihnen das Bezeugen von 
Mitleid das groesste Gut von der Welt ausmache.
</foreign></p>
<p>Of course one ought to <em>express</em> pity, but one ought to guard against 
<em>having</em> it; for unfortunate people are so <em>stupid</em> that they 
count the expression of pity as the greatest good on earth.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 50</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
das Mitleiden, welches Jene dann aeussern, ist insofern eine Troestung fuer die 
Schwachen und Leidenden, als sie daran erkennen, doch wenigstens noch Eine Macht 
zu haben, trotz aller ihrer Schwaeche: die Macht, wehe zu thun.
</foreign></p>
<p>The pity that the spectators then express consoles the weak and suffering, 
inasmuch as they see that, despite all their weakness, they still <em>have</em> 
at least one <em>power</em>: <em>the power to hurt</em>.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 50</source>
<note>The latter quote is part of a counter to the former.</note>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Aber wird es viele Ehrliche geben, welche zugestehen, dass es Vergnuegen macht, 
wehe zu thun?
</foreign></p>
<p>But will there be many people honest enough to admit that it is a pleasure 
to inflict pain?
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 50</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Einer der gewoehnlichen Fehlschluesse ist der: weil Jemand wahr und aufrichtig 
gegen uns ist, so sagt er die Wahrheit.
</foreign></p>
<p>One common false conclusion is that because someone is truthful and upright 
towards us he is speaking the truth.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 53</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Isn't it clear that, in all these cases [of selflessness] man is loving 
<em>something of himself</em>, a thought, a longing, an offspring, more than 
<em>something else of himself</em>, that he is thus <em>dividing up</em> his 
being and sacrificing one part 
for the other?
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 57</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Man kann Handlungen versprechen, aber keine Empfindungen; denn diese sind 
unwillkuerlich. Wer jemandem verspricht, ihn immer zu lieben oder immer zu 
hassen oder ihm immer treu zu sein, verspricht Etwas, das nicht in seiner 
Macht steht
</foreign></p>
<p>One can promise actions, but not feelings, for the latter are involuntary. 
He who promises to love forever or hate forever or be forever faithful to 
someone is promising something that is not in his power.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 58</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Passion will not wait.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 61</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
[P]erhaps the great majority of men find it necessary, in order to maintain 
their self respect and a certain effectiveness in their actions, to lower 
and belittle the image they form of everyone they know.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 63</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
If looks could kill, we would long ago have been done for.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 64</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Often it is success that gives to a deed the full, honest lustre of a good 
conscience; failure lays the shadow of an uneasy conscience upon the most 
estimable action.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 65</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
In truth, [hope] is the most evil of evils because it prolongs man's torment.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 71</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
One will seldom go wrong to attribute extreme actions to vanity, moderate ones 
to habit and petty ones to fear.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 74</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
[I]t is automatically assumed that the perpetrator and sufferer think and 
feel the same, and the guilt of one is therefore measured by the pain of the 
other.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 81</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
When virtue has slept, it will arise refreshed.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 83</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Men are not ashamed to think something dirty, but they are ashamed when they 
imagine that others might believe them capable of these dirty thoughts.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 84</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Most men are much too concerned with themselves to be malicious.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 85</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
We praise or find fault, depending on which of the two provides more opportunity 
for our powers of judgement to shine.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 86</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
He who humbleth himself wants to be exalted.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 87</source>
<note>'Improvement' of Luke 18:14 - "He who humbleth himself shall be 
exalted".</note>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
[T]he initial character of justice is <em>barter</em>.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 92</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p><foreign>
Unusquisque tantum juris habet, quantum potentia valere creditur 
</foreign></p>
<p>
Each has as much right as his power is assessed to be.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 93</source>
<note>Based on a quote by Spinoza: <foreign>Unusquisque tantum juris habet, 
quantum potentia valet</foreign> Each has as much right as his power is worth.
</note>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
[W]e all still suffer from too slight a regard for our own personal needs; it 
has been poorly developed.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 95</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Socrates and Plato were right: whatever man does, he always acts for the good; 
that is, in a way which seems to him good (useful) according to the degree of 
his intellect, the prevailing measure of his rationality.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 102</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Is <foreign>Schadenfreude</foreign> devilish ... Is the <em>knowledge</em>, 
then, that another person is suffering because of us supposed to make immoral 
the same thing about which we would otherwise feel no responsibility?
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 103</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
If one does not know how painful an action is, it cannot be malicious; thus the 
child is not malicious or evil to an animal: he examines and destroys it like a 
toy.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 104</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
No life without pleasure, the struggle for pleasure is the struggle for life.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 104</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Between good and evil actions there is no difference in type; at most a 
difference in degree. Good actions are sublimated evil actions; evil actions 
are good actions become coarse and stupid.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
On the History of Moral Feelings, Aphorism 107</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
The thinking of men who believe in magic and miracles is bent on <em>imposing</em> 
a law on nature; and in short, religious worship is the result of this thinking.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
Religious Life, Aphorism 111</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
When we hear the old bells ringing out on a Sunday morning, we ask ourselves: 
can it be possible? This is for a Jew, crucified two thousand years ago, who 
said he was the son of God. The proof for such a claim is wanting.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
Religious Life, Aphorism 113</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Christianity came into being in order to lighten the heart; but now it has to 
burden the heart first, in order to be able to lighten it afterwards. 
Consequently it will perish.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
Religious Life, Aphorism 119</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Without blind disciples, no man or his work has ever gained great influence.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
Religious Life, Aphorism 122</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
There is not enough love and kindness in the world to permit us to give any of 
it away to imaginary beings.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
Religious Life, Aphorism 129</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
In each ascetic morality, man prays to one part of himself as a god and also 
finds it necessary to diabolify the rest.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
Religious Life, Aphorism 137</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
What do we long for when we see beauty? To be beautiful. We think much happiness 
must be connected with it. But that is an error.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
From the Soul of Artists and Writers, Aphorism 149</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Art renders the sight of life bearable by laying over it the gauze of impure 
thinking.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
From the Soul of Artists and Writers, Aphorism 151</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Every great phenomenon is followed by degeneration, particularly in the realm 
of art. The model of the great man stimulates vainer natures to imitate him 
outwardly or to surpass him; in addition, all great talents have the fateful 
quantity of stifling many weaker forces and seeds, and seem to devastate the 
nature around them. The most fortunate instance in the development of an art 
is when several geniuses reciprocally keep each other in check; in this kind 
of a struggle, weaker and gentler natures are generally also allowed air and 
light.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
From the Soul of Artists and Writers, Aphorism 158</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Just as youth and childhood have value <em>in and of themselves</em> ... 
so too do unfinished thoughts have their own value.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
From the Soul of Artists and Writers, Aphorism 207</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Every writer is surprised anew when a book, as soon as it has been separated 
from him, begins to take on a life of its own ... it goes about finding its 
readers, kindles life, pleases, horrifies, fathers new works, becomes the soul
of others' resolutions and behaviour. In short, it lives like a being fitted 
out with a mind and soul--yet it is nevertheless not human.
</p>
<author>Friedrich Nietzsche</author>
<source><cite>Human, All Too Human</cite> 
From the Soul of Artists and Writers, Aphorism 208</source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
[O]fficial thieves were rare in the Ramtops, where people weren't
rich enough to afford them.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Mort</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
The Creator had a lot of remarkably good ideas when he put the world 
together, but making it understandable hadn't been one of them.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Mort</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
It was crowded in the Curry Gardens on the corner of God Street and
Blood Alley, but only with the cream of society - at least, with those
people who are found floating on the top and who, therefore, it's
wisest to call the cream.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Mort</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
They walked out through the wall. He was halfway after them before he
realised that walking through walls was impossible.
</p>
<p>
The suicidal logic of this nearly killed him. He felt the chill of the
stone around his limbs before a voice in his ear said:
</p>
<p>
LOOK AT IT THIS WAY. THE WALL CANT BE THERE. OTHERWISE YOU WOULDN'T BE
WALKING THROUGH IT. WOULD YOU, BOY?
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Mort</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
There was a certain something about the air in the city.
You got the feeling that it was air that had seen life. You couldn't
help noting with every breath that thousands of other people were very
close to you and nearly all of them had armpits.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Mort</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
There had been a sound like someone making no noise at all. Forget
peas and mattresses - sheer natural selection had established over the
years that the royal families that survived longest were those whose
members could distinguish an assassin in the dark by the noise he was
clever enough not to make, because, in court circles, there was always
someone ready to cut the heir with a knife.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Mort</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Ysabell sighed. 'Look, how about this? Let's pretend we've had the row
and I've won. See? It saves a lot of effort.'
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Mort</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Only one creature could have duplicated the expressions on their
faces, and that would be a pigeon who has heard not only that Lord
Nelson has got down off his column but has also been seen buying a
12-bore repeater and a box of cartridges.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Mort</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
There should be a word for that brief period just after waking when
the mind is full of warm pink nothing. You lie there entirely empty of
thought, except for a growing suspicion that heading towards you, like
a sockful of damp sand in a nocturnal alleyway, are all the
recollections you'd really rather do without, and which amount to the
fact that the only mitigating factor in your horrible future is the
certainty that it will be quite short.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Mort</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
But at least the way was clear now. When you step off
a cliff, your life takes a very definite direction.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Mort</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Then there's all that business with goat-headed gods. Most witches don't believe
in gods. They know that the gods exist, of course. They even deal with them 
occasionally. But they don't believe in them. They know them too well. It would 
be like believing in the postman.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Witches Abroad</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
The Oggs contained, in just one family, enough feuds to keep an entire Ozark of
normal hillbillies going for a century.
</p>

<p>
And sometimes this encouraged a foolish outsider to join in and perhaps make an
uncomplimentary remark about one Ogg to another Ogg. Whereupon every single Ogg
would turn on him, every part of the family closing up together like the parts of 
a well-oiled, blue-steeled engine to deal instant merciless destruction to the
interloper.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Witches Abroad</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
They were the kind of mountains where winters went for their summer holidays.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Witches Abroad</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Most people, on waking up, accelerate through a quick panicky pre-consciousness
check-up: who am I, where am I, who is he/she, good god, why am I cuddling a 
policeman's helmet, what happened last night?
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Witches Abroad</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
It was like getting muddy. Getting muddy when you had a nice hot tub to look 
forward to was fun; getting muddy when all you had to look forward to was more 
mud was no fun at all.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Witches Abroad</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
It is a universal fact that any innocent comment made by any recently-married 
young member of any workforce is an instant trigger for coarse merriment among 
his or her older and more cynical colleagues. This happens even if everyone 
concerned has nine legs and lives at the bottom of an ocean of ammonia on a huge 
cold planet.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Witches Abroad</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
The wages of sin is death but so is the salary of virtue, and at least the evil 
get to go home early on Fridays.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Witches Abroad</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Cats are like witches. They don't fight to kill, but to win. There is a 
difference. There's no point in killing an opponent. That way, they won't know 
they've lost, and to be a real winner you have to have an opponent who is beaten 
and knows it. There's no triumph over a corpse, but a beaten opponent, who will 
remain beaten every day of the remainder of their sad and wretched life, is 
something to treasure.
</p>
<author>Terry Pratchett</author>
<source><cite>Witches Abroad</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
The fact is, that there was considerable difficulty in inducing Oliver to
take upon himself the office of respiration,--a troublesome
practice, but one which custom has rendered necessary to our easy
existence
</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Oliver Twist</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Now, if, during this brief period, Oliver had been surrounded by
careful grandmothers, anxious aunts, experienced nurses, and
doctors of profound wisdom, he would most inevitably and
indubitably have been killed in no time.
</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Oliver Twist</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
What an excellent example of the power of dress, young Oliver
Twist was!  Wrapped in the blanket which had hitherto formed his
only covering, he might have been the child of a nobleman or a
beggar; it would have been hard for the haughtiest stranger to
have assigned him his proper station in society.  But now that he
was enveloped in the old calico robes which had grown yellow in
the same service, he was badged and ticketed, and fell into his
place at once--a parish child--the orphan of a workhouse--the
humble, half-starved drudge--to be cuffed and buffeted through
the world--despised by all, and pitied by none.
</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Oliver Twist</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Oliver cried lustily. If he could have known that he was an
orphan, left to the tender mercies of church-wardens and
overseers, perhaps he would have cried the louder.
</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Oliver Twist</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
The elderly female was a woman of wisdom
and experience; she knew what was good for children; and she had
a very accurate perception of what was good for herself.  So, she
appropriated the greater part of the weekly stipend to her own
use, and consigned the rising parochial generation to even a
shorter allowance than was originally provided for them.  Thereby
finding in the lowest depth a deeper still; and proving herself a
very great experimental philosopher.
</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Oliver Twist</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
What a novel illustration of the tender laws of England!  They let the paupers
go to sleep!
</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Oliver Twist</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
If a dread of not being understood be hidden in the breasts of
other young people to anything like the extent to which it used to
be hidden in mine,--which I consider probable, as I have no
particular reason to suspect myself of having been a monstrosity,--
it is the key to many reservations.
</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Great Expectations</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Heaven knows we need never be ashamed of our tears, for they are
rain upon the blinding dust of earth, overlying our hard hearts.
</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Great Expectations</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
Herbert Pocket had a frank and easy way with him that was very
taking.  I had never seen any one then, and I have never seen any
one since, who more strongly expressed to me, in every look and
tone, a natural incapacity to do anything secret and mean.  There
was something wonderfully hopeful about his general air, and
something that at the same time whispered to me he would never be
very successful or rich.
</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Great Expectations</cite></source>
</quotation>

<quotation>
<p>
So, throughout life, our worst weaknesses and meannesses are usually committed 
for the sake of the people whom we most despise.
</p>
<author>Charles Dickens</author>
<source><cite>Great Expectations</cite></source>
</quotation>

</quotations>
